# KATELYN MICHALOVE

Product Designer

katelynmichalove@gmail.com

katelynmichalove.com

615-613-5617

### **SUMMARY**

I am a Product Designer with skills in conducting user research, leading projects, wireframing, visual design, and using and contributing to design systems. I've collaborated with executives, outside design vendors, end users, and internal teams to reach multiple product goals. My goal is to solve for user needs while balancing and meeting business objectives.

## SKILL SET

UX/UI Design Visual Design

User Research

Market Research

**Usability Testing** 

Information Architecture

**Branding** 

Prototyping

Frontend Development

# **TOOLS**

Adobe Creative Suite
Optimal Workshop
Usability Hub
Lookback, Loom
Omnigraffle, Axure
Sketch, Figma
InVision, Marvel
Git & GitHub
HTML, CSS
Jira

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Sunbelt Rentals / Product Designer**

July 2019 - present Charlotte. NC

#### • VDOS- Vehicle Dispatch Software

Product redesign involving field interviews and observations, wireframing new solutions and features to solve dispatcher needs, using the design system while adding new necessary visual components, usability testing and iteration.

- SmartEquip iOS Mobile Inspection Application
  - 1 Week sprint redesign to improve the user flows, match iOS HIG, convert visual design to Sunbelt branding guidelines, and create new necessary visual components. Later, an additional use case to solve for a UX problem encountered in pilot.
- SunbeltRentals.com Customer facing website
   Performed usability testing, card sorting exercises, and wireframes for new section of the website.

#### Freelance / Product Designer

August 2018- July 2019 Remote

- UX Design- Competitive Analysis, User Stories, User Flows,
   Wireframing, Prototyping, User Testing
- Visual Design- Branding, High Fidelity Mockups, Prototyping, User Testing, Webflow

#### **Procter and Gamble / Process Engineer**

June 2017 - July 2018 Sacramento, CA

 Led troubleshooting group through the stages of problem solving from exploration to documentation.

# **EDUCATION**

**University of Tennessee** / 2017 / BA Chemical Engineering

**Bloc** / 2019 / UX Design Apprenticeship Remote program focused on designing 5 projects with consistent feedback through mentorship, grading team, and daily design critiques.